Each commit has a unique set of characters - an identifier (also called hash). Using a hash, you can see all the changes made within one commit:
The simplest analytics is performed with the git log command. It shows a list of all completed commits, sorted by date added. At the top we see the most recent commits:
What if we don’t know the commit, but we’re wondering who last changed a specific line in the file? The command git blame <path to file> is suitable for this. This command outputs the file and next to each line it shows who changed it and in which commit:

The git grep command searches all files in the project for a match of the specified string. This is a very convenient command for quick analysis from the terminal. It is more convenient than regular grep, because it knows about ignoring and does not look in the .git directory, and can also search by history:
